<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>aayush's blog</title><link>https://blog.aayushdev.xyz/</link><description>Recent content on aayush's blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © 2025, Aayush Chaudhary.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:30:55 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.aayushdev.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bluesky Fresh Breath</title><link>https://blog.aayushdev.xyz/posts/bluesky-fresh-breath/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 19:30:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.aayushdev.xyz/posts/bluesky-fresh-breath/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="bluesky-a-fresh-breath">Bluesky a fresh breath&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Bluesky has been a new emergence as twitter alternatives. Although, from the get go I wansn&amp;rsquo;t very attracted to Twitter. The UI is too populated and everyone&amp;rsquo;s shouting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bluesky seems quiter, not many people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although, its counter-intuitive - I get less eyes on my work. Even so, I prefer it for the same reason. I wanna be seen but not too much.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="why-bsky">Why BSky?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Its been about 25 days since I started posting there. I am able to talk anything, not many will see it, nor it would be judged.
But, my orignal intent was increase reach on my reserach interests and possibly land a job via networking and public learning.
That hasn&amp;rsquo;t been going so well. I just post about what happend throughout my day. And one thing that I did related to coding.
I need to follow a structured approach to this.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflection | Life Update</title><link>https://blog.aayushdev.xyz/posts/reflection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 08:23:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.aayushdev.xyz/posts/reflection/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reflection | Life Update&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Looking back at the past few months, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had the luxury of reflecting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I usually stop by and look at where I am headed in life. What am I trying to do? What did I do wrong? These questions often lead to hours of monologue with myself and my journal.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are less career-oriented. Strange to put it this way, but not all reflection, self-growth and pondering have to be career-related. There&amp;rsquo;s more to life than just a job that turns me into a cog and wears me down -till I&amp;rsquo;m 60.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Moments Over Pixels</title><link>https://blog.aayushdev.xyz/posts/moments-over-pixels/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://blog.aayushdev.xyz/posts/moments-over-pixels/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="moments-over-pixels">Moments over pixels&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One should buy a budget camera + a cheaper phone than a flagship phone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>MKBHD says, &amp;ldquo;What is a photo?&amp;rdquo;. We&amp;rsquo;ve come so far in computational photography that computed photos are indistinguishable from real ones. I recently tried Google&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;Add Me&amp;rsquo;, and it&amp;rsquo;s really believable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In general, I do not like the ease of photos. How we feel every moment needs to be captured and why we need only the top x phone to get the best moments possible.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>